A little anti. A little hero.
Nimona is a animation, family, action film directed by Troy Quane.
A knight framed for a tragic crime teams with a scrappy,
shape-shifting teen to prove his innocence.
Nimona (voice), played by Chloë Grace Moretz.
Ballister Boldheart (voice), played by Riz Ahmed.
Ambrosius Goldenloin (voice), played by Eugene Lee Yang.
The Director (voice), played by Frances Conroy.
Queen Valerin (voice), played by Lorraine Toussaint.
Sir Thoddeus Sureblade (voice), played by Beck Bennett.
Nimona is a 2023 American animated science fantasy action-adventure film directed by Nick
Bruno and Troy Quane, based on the 2015 graphic novel by ND Stevenson.
Set in a medieval-futuristic kingdom, the film features the voices of Chloë Grace Moretz as the eponymous shapeshifting character and
Riz Ahmed as her boss and former knight Ballister, with Eugene Lee Yang and Frances Conroy voicing supporting roles.
The story follows Ballister who, after he is framed for the murder of the
Queen, teams up with Nimona on a mission to clear his name.
Originally a production of Blue Sky Studios, it was set to be directed by
Patrick Osborne, with an initial release date of 2020.
Following the Walt Disney Company's acquisition of 21st Century Fox, the parent company of Blue Sky, it
was delayed a couple times before being canceled due to Blue Sky's closure in April 2021.
However, Annapurna Pictures revived the project the following year, with Bruno and Quane announced as
directors, DNEG Animation providing animation, and Netflix acquiring worldwide distribution.
Christophe Beck was hired to compose the film's rock-inspired score.
Nimona had its world premiere at the Annecy International Animation Film Festival on June 14, 2023,
was released in select cinemas on June 23, and made its streaming debut on June 30.
The film received critical acclaim and was nominated for Best Animated
Feature at the Critics' Choice, Annie Awards and Academy Awards.
The film explores themes of monster, supernatural, on
the run, knight, based on graphic novel.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.